# Kailani Chu

(808) 895-8882 | 154 Waianuenue Ave #11082, Hilo, HI 96721 | me@kailani.io kailani.io | github.com/hawaiigal | linkedin.com/in/kailanichu

#### **Interests**

My research interests are in utilizing programming language techniques such as type systems and runtime verification to build secure and performant systems. My past experiences include scalable systems programming (C/C++/Go/Rust), programming language analysis, and information retrieval.

#### Education

### **Northeastern University**

**Boston, MA** 

College of Computer and Information Science

September 2016 - May 2020

B.S. in Computer Science, Magna Cum Laude, Dean's List

GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

Capstone Project: A compiler with type inference and GC in OCaml for AMD64

#### **Skills**

Languages

Python, Java, Rust, Go, C++, C, Ruby, OCaml, JavaScript, SQL, KQL, Bash

**Technologies** 

Ruby on Rails, MySQL8, CosmosDB, Kafka, Airflow, Redis, GraphQL, Linux, Git Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, OpenAPI, Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure

# **Industry Experience**

GitHub

Remote

Software Engineer on Code Search

December 2024 - Present

- Improving GitHub's highly available, scalable code search engine for millions of developers on GitHub and powering semantic/vector search for Microsoft Copilot AI for millions more
- Assisted in productionizing embeddings code indexing infrastructure for LLMs, enabling free access to VSCode Copilot AI features

Software Engineer on Security Products

February 2022 - December 2024

- Implemented support for Private Registries in Dependabot Alerts, allowing customers to automatically resolve and update vulnerabilities within packages from private package registries
- Released GitHub Private Vulnerability Reporting to facilitate safe and confidential vulnerability disclosure, helping publish nearly 500 security advisories in 12 months
- Spearheaded API and storage design for Vulnerability Reachability Analysis to identify critical exploitable vulnerabilities and improve supply chain security across repositories on GitHub
- Expanded GitHub Advisory Database coverage by adding new vulnerability sources and ecosystems

Google Sunnyvale, CA

Software Engineer on Google Payments

August 2021 - February 2022

- Developed features to improve Google Pay balance payment flows, reducing user declines
- Built and improved APIs to enable instant, safe, and consistent checkout experiences

### **Industry Experience Continued**

Google Sunnyvale, CA

Software Engineer on Cloud Platforms

July 2020 - August 2021

- Designed and implemented a software platform to detect and log instantaneous datacenter anomalies, enabling SREs to better root-cause transient outages
- Served as software lead across multiple datacenter power hardware projects to improve efficiency and stability and reduce total cost of ownership
- Created new firmware verification and testing systems, reducing regressions in production
- Interfaced with external teams and vendors to create software solutions for custom datacenter hardware

Software Engineering Intern on Cloud Platforms

May 2019 - August 2019

- Developed a Kythe source code indexer for SystemVerilog, enabling advanced code analysis for Google Code Search used by tens of thousands of engineers across Alphabet.
- Added support for advanced code insight features in Google internal IDEs
- Improved build and developer tooling to support Tensor Processing Unit (TPU) chip design efforts

Salsify Boston, MA

Software Engineer Co-op on Platform Foundations

January 2019 - May 2019

- Designed and implemented standard error handling in the new customer-facing GraphQL Rails API, improving UX and developer productivity
- Completed implementation of multilingual support on the Salsify platform
- Assisted the design of complex product data modeling capabilities

#### **Thermo Fisher Scientific**

Boston, MA

Software Engineer Co-op

January 2018 - May 2018

- Designed, implemented, and released a low-cost distributed air quality monitoring software/hardware platform for use in China and developing countries
- Developed a custom Linux userspace I2C driver in C++11 to allow unified management and communication with dozens of connected devices
- Created a custom visual testing harness to automate UI regression detection for scientific instruments

# **Teaching Experience**

### **Northeastern University**

Boston, MA

Head Teaching Assistant for Object Oriented Programming Teaching Assistant for Computer Systems Teaching Assistant for Introduction to Embedded Design January 2020 - May 2020 January 2020 - May 2020 September 2019 - December 2019